William Allan Neilson Personal Papers, 1852-1946 RG 32.02.personal
Smith College Archives
- Series IV. OTHER ACTIVITIES, 1891-1946; 4.5 linear feet
  - Subjects
    - Russia
      - Independent Committee for the Recognition of Soviet Russia by the United States, 1933-1935 (Box 32, Folder 651)
      - American Russian Institute, 1930-1939 (Box 32, Folder 652-53)
      - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1927-1929 (Box 32, Folder 654-55)
    - Scots
      - Miscellaneous: correspondence, news clipping, 1930-1939 (Box 32, Folder 656)
      - Scots' Charitable Society, 1917-1927 (Box 32, Folder 657)
      - Scottish National Dictionary Association, 1927-1934 (Box 32, Folder 658)
      - Scottish Text Society, 1903-1934 (Box 32, Folder 659)
    - Shakespeare: miscellaneous (Box 32, Folder 660)
    - Shakespeare: Shakespeare Association of America, 1923-1930 (Box 32, Folder 661)
    - Social hygiene, 1920-1928 (Box 32, Folder 662)
    - Social sciences: miscellaneous, 1918-1934 (Box 32, Folder 663)
    - Social sciences: Social Science Commission, undated (Box 32, Folder 664)
    - Social work, 1922-1930 (Box 32, Folder 665)
    - Spain, miscellaneous: correspondence, news clippings, 1921-1940 (Box 32, Folder 666)
    - Spain: Non-Partisan Committee for the Relief of Spain's Children, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 667)
    - Springfield: miscellaneous, 1928-1936 (Box 32, Folder 668)
    - Springfield: Springfield College, 1936-1937 (Box 32, Folder 669)
    - Unemployment, 1927-1933 (Box 32, Folder 670)
    - World Court, 1921-1935 (Box 32, Folder 671)
  - Oversize
    - American Civil Liberties Union, Committee on Academic Freedom: ms., undated (Box 33, Folder 672)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: correspondence and publications Elizabeth Gurley Flynn case, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 673)
    - American Civil Liberties Union: miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 674)
- Series V. SPEECHES, 1901-1944; 2.5 linear feet
  This series is divided into five sections: 'Texts-by title;' 'Texts-by date;' 'Texts-by occasion;' 'Notes;' and 'Miscellany.'
  The texts have been divided into three categories depending on the information available about the speech. Each text that has a title has been filed alphabetically. Other texts have been filed chronologically (where possible) or by occasion. Unless otherwise noted the texts are in typed or printed form.
  'Notes' have also been filed by available information. They are all in Neilson's hand.
  'Miscellany' is primarily news clippings and correspondence about Neilson's speeches but also contains a list of the topics of Neilson's Smith College Chapel talks from 1934 to 1936.
  - Texts - by title
    - "After Victory," chapel, 1918 (Box 34, Folder 675)
    - "The American Scholar Today," American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1936 January 1 (Box 34, Folder 676)
    - "America's Dilemma," Rally Day, 1941 February (Box 34, Folder 677)
    - "And Ye Shall Hallow the 50th Year," chapel, 1925 (Box 34, Folder 678)
    - "The Arts In the Colleges," radio broadcast, 1935 May 17 (Box 34, Folder 679)
    - "As Shakespeare Says", undated (Box 34, Folder 680)
    - "Current Criticism of Higher Education," Chicago Smith Club, 1936 November 6 (Box 34, Folder 681)
    - "Distinguishing Characteristics of American Education," Alumnae College, 1936 June (Box 34, Folder 682)
    - "Education and Politics," Aydelotte Lecture, Swarthmore College, 1940 October 13 (Box 34, Folder 683)
    - "Ends and Means in Education," Felix Adler Lecture, Society for Ethical Culture, 1940 May 12 (Box 34, Folder 684)
    - "From the Point of View of a Professor Turned President," Modern Language Association, 1924; December 29 (Box 34, Folder 685)
    - "The Function of the University," Northwestern University: ms, 1943 April 8 (Box 34, Folder 686)
    - "The Function of the University": published version, 1943 (Box 34, Folder 687)
    - "George Washington Cable", undated (Box 34, Folder 688)
    - "Germany Today," Alumnae College, 1934 June 23 (Box 34, Folder 689)
    - "Guarding the Line," chapel, 1942 February 9 (Box 34, Folder 690)
    - "The Heart of the Midlothian," NBC University of the Air, 1944 November 25 (Box 34, Folder 691)
    - "The Inauguration of Dr. Marian E. Park as President of Bryn Mawr College", undated (Box 34, Folder 692)
    - "Inter Arma Veritas," Phi Beta Kappa, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 693)
    - "The League and Future International Relations", undated (Box 34, Folder 694)
    - "Looking Backward and Forward", 1935 May 6 (Box 34, Folder 695)
    - "The Meaning of Americanism," DAR Springfield, 1920 December 16 (Box 34, Folder 696)
    - "The Meaning of Liberalism," Why Club, 1928 (Box 34, Folder 697)
    - "National Training of Women", 1943 November (Box 34, Folder 698)
    - "Nazi Germany as a Threat to Our Liberties," Duke University Commencement, 1940 June 3 (Box 34, Folder 699)
    - "Our Fundamental Political Ideas in Light of Recent Events," Alumnae Council, 1937 February (Box 34, Folder 700)
    - "The Paradox of the Colleges", undated (Box 34, Folder 701)
    - "The Poetry of Liberalism," Alumnae College, 1939 June 16 (Box 34, Folder 702)
    - "President Eliot's Educational Ideas", 1934 March 21 (Box 34, Folder 703)
    - "President Neilson Proposes," Brearly School 50th Anniversary, 1934 (Box 34, Folder 703a)
    - "President Pendleton As An Educator", undated (Box 34, Folder 704)
    - "The Progress of Peace", 1930 January (Box 34, Folder 705)
    - "Public Affairs and the Private Conscience," vespers, 1938 September 25 (Box 34, Folder 706)
    - "The Relation of the Women's Colleges to American Education," Seven College Conference, undated (Box 34, Folder 707)
    - "Rights and Duties," chapel, 1937 October 19 (Box 34, Folder 708)
    - "The Scholar and the Pedant," Vassar Inauguration, undated (Box 34, Folder 709)
    - "Shall We Join the Ladies?" Seven College Conference, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 710)
    - "A Tradition Worth Cherishing," Alumnae Assembly, 1942 June 6 (Box 34, Folder 711)
    - "To the Alumnae of the Mary A. Burnham School", undated (Box 34, Folder 712)
    - "Les Universites et L'Etat," Sorbonne, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 713)
    - "The University in Exile," New School for Social Research, 1933 October 13 (Box 34, Folder 714)
    - "Which Girl Should Go to College?" radio broadcast, 1929 October 10 (Box 34, Folder 715)
    - "The World Crisis in Education," New York Smith Club, 1934 March 10 (Box 34, Folder 716)
  - Texts - by date
    - Miscellaneous, 1907-1935 (Box 35, Folder 717-742)
    - Miscellaneous, 1936-1941 (Box 36, Folder 743-63)
  - Texts - by occasion
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 36, Folder 764-65)
    - President Seelye's Funeral Service, 1924 (Box 36, Folder 765a)
    - Smith Baccalaureate, undated (Box 36, Folder 766)
    - Smith Chapel, undated (Box 36, Folder 767-74)
  - Notes
    - Chronological, 1901-1943 (Box 37, Folder 775-77)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 37, Folder 778-79)
    - Baccalaureate, 1918-1937 (Box 37, Folder 780)
    - Vespers, 1917-1938 (Box 37, Folder 781-83)
    - Vespers, undated (Box 37, Folder 784)
    - Shakespeare, undated (Box 37, Folder 785)
  - Miscellany
    - Smith Chapel topics list, 1934-1936 (Box 37, Folder 786)
    - News clippings, 1916-1935 (Box 37, Folder 787-95)
    - News clippings, 1936-1943; undated (Box 38, Folder 796-802)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1940; undated (Box 39, Folder 803-827)
- Series VI. WRITINGS, 1894-1946; 5.5 linear feet
  This series has two sections: 'Texts and Notes' and 'Correspondence and News Clippings.'
  'Texts and Notes' is made up of manuscript, typescript, and published versions of articles and books by William Allan Neilson. They are filed by the title of the work. Reviews written by Neilson are filed at the end of the section.
  'Correspondence and News Clippings' contains correspondence with editors, collaborators, publishers, and fans plus press releases, new clippings, and reviews. They are filed by the title of the work. Also included is correspondence from publishers of periodicals soliciting manuscripts. These are filed together under 'periodicals.'
  - Texts and notes
    - Bibliography (Box 40, Folder 828)
    - "The Accomplishment of President Comstock," Radcliffe Quarterly, 1943 August (Box 40, Folder 829)
    - "The Administrative View of Organized Alumni," Manual of Alumni Work, 1924 (Box 40, Folder 830)
    - "Admissions, the Depression, & Scholarships," Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1931 November (Box 40, Folder 831)
    - The Alumnae Fund and Salaries, Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1927 May (Box 40, Folder 832)
    - Allegory (unpublished): miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 833-36)
    - Allegory (unpublished): typescript, undated (Box 40, Folder 837-41)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Allegory": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 842)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Faerie Queen": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 843)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Shepheard's Calendar": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 844)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Bunyan": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 845)
    - Allegory (unpublished) "Addison: Tatler no. 97": ms., incomplete, undated (Box 40, Folder 846)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Pastoral Allegory": ms., incomplete, undated (Box 40, Folder 847)
    - Allegory (unpublished), Chapter I "The Nature of Allegory": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 848)
    - Allegory (unpublished), Chapter II "Origins": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 849)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Pier's Plowman": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 850)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "John Gower": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 851)
    - Allegory (unpublished) "Chaucer": notes and draft, undated (Box 40, Folder 852)
    - Allegory (unpublished) "The Legend of Good Women": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 853)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Lydgate": outline, undated (Box 40, Folder 854)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Reason and Sensibility": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 855)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Temple of Glass": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 856)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Assembly of the Gods": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 857)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Assembly of Ladies": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 858)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Scottish School": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 859)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Robert Henryson": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 860)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Beauty and the Prisoner": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 861)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "William Dunbar": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 862)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Gavin Douglas" and "Stephen Hawes": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 863)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Court of Love": ms. and notes, undated (Box 40, Folder 864)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Moralities": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 865)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "The Allegorical Testament": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 866)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Keats": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 867)
    - Allegory (unpublished), "Tennyson": ms., undated (Box 40, Folder 868)
    - Allegory (unpublished): miscellaneous, undated (Box 40, Folder 869)
    - "The American Scholar Today" (Hampshire Bookshop), 1937 (Box 41, Folder 870)
    - "America's Dilemma," Defense Pamphlet No. 1, 1941 (Box 41, Folder 871)
    - "The Apparel and the Man," Atlantic Monthly, 1903 May (Box 41, Folder 872)
    - "Are American Colleges Wasteful?" Scribner's Magazine, 1932 June (Box 41, Folder 873)
    - "Burns In English," Anniversary Papers by Colleagues and Pupils of George Lyman Kittredge, 1913 (Box 41, Folder 874)
    - Burns, Robert: miscellaneous articles and fragments, undated (Box 41, Folder 875)
    - "Challenge to Our Colleges," New York Times Magazine, 1942 June 7 (Box 41, Folder 876)
    - "Character Drawing in the Waverly Novels," Harvard Monthly, 1896 November (Box 41, Folder 877)
    - The City of Man, "A Declaration of World Democracy", 1940 (Box 41, Folder 878-79)
    - The City of Man: first memorandum, 1939 May (Box 41, Folder 880)
    - The City of Man: note, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 881)
    - The City of Man: proposa1, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 882)
    - "College Finances of the Increase of Fees," Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1926 February (Box 41, Folder 883)
    - Collier's Encyclopedia: preface by WAN: ms. and typescript, undated (Box 41, Folder 884)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare: miscellaneous, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 885)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare: biographical sketch, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 886)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "All's Well That Ends Well": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 887)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "The Comedy of Errors": introduction and proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 888)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Coriolanus": proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 889)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Cymbeline": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 890)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Henry IV, part 1": introduction and notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 891)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Henry IV, part 2": introduction and notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 892)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Henry V": notes and proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 893)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Henry VI, parts 1, 2 and 3": notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 894)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Henry VIII": notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 895)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "King Lear": notes and proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 896-97)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "The Life and Death of King John": introduction and notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 898)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Love's Labour's Lost": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 899)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Measure for Measure": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 900)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "The Merry Wives of Windsor": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 901)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "A Midsummer-Night's Dream": introduction and proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 902)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Richard II": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 903)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Richard III": notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 904)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Romeo and Juliet": notes and proofs, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 905)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "The Tempest": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 906)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Timon of Athens": notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 907)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare, "Troilus and Cressida": introduction, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 908)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare: notes, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 909-10)
    - The Complete Plays and Poems of William Shakespeare: notes, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 911-12)
    - "The Curse of Memory," The English Journal, 1917 February (Box 42, Folder 913)
    - "Education Can Be No Better Than the Teachers," Survey Graphic, 1939 October (Box 42, Folder 914)
    - The Education of the Modern Girl: Introductory Note by WAN, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 915)
    - "Charles William Eliot," Encyclopedia of the Social Services, Vol. 5, 1931 (Box 42, Folder 916)
    - Charles William Eliot: miscellaneous articles and fragments, undated (Box 42, Folder 917)
    - "The Elizabethan Drama," Harvard Lectures, 1913 (Box 42, Folder 918)
    - "English," in Paths to Success, compiled by H.G. Black, 1924 (Box 42, Folder 919)
    - "Faculty and Alumni": ms., undated (Box 42, Folder 920)
    - "Fundamental Problems," Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1939 January 13 (Box 42, Folder 921)
    - "Horace Howard Furness", undated (Box 42, Folder 922)
    - "The Future of the Humanities," Harper's Magazine: ms., 1943 March (Box 42, Folder 923)
    - "Guarding the Line," Defense Pamphlet No. 4 (Hampshire Bookshop), 1942 (Box 42, Folder 924)
    - Harvard Classics: index and miscellaneous, undated (Box 42, Folder 925)
    - Harvard Classics: "Shelf of Fiction," biographical notes, undated (Box 42, Folder 926)
    - "Henry Drummond - A Memory": ms., undated (Box 42, Folder 927)
    - History of English Literature: "A Manual for Teachers" with A. H. Thorndike, 1920 (Box 42, Folder 928)
    - The Junior Classics: introduction, undated (Box 42, Folder 929)
    - "Junior Year In France": ms., undated (Box 42, Folder 930)
    - "The Juniors Abroad," Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1937 May (Box 42, Folder 931)
    - "The Liberal Arts as Vocational Training", 1924 (Box 42, Folder 932)
    - "The Life of the Teacher of Composition," New England Association of Teachers of English, 1912 (Box 42, Folder 933)
    - Merriam-Webster Dictionary of Biography: articles on Burns and Shakespeare, undated (Box 42, Folder 934)
    - "Minorities in Our Midst," Survey Graphic, 1939 February (Box 42, Folder 935)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1925; undated (Box 42, Folder 936)
    - "Narrative Writing in Medieval Times," The Reader, 1906 February (Box 42, Folder 937)
    - Normal Youth and Its Everyday Problems by Douglas A. Thom: introduction by WAN, 1932 (Box 42, Folder 938)
    - "A Note on Graduate Projects," Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1929 February (Box 42, Folder 939)
    - "A Note on Scholarships." Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1927 February (Box 42, Folder 940)
    - "Nova Solyma," Modern Philology, 1904 April (Box 42, Folder 941)
    - "On Milton's Conception of Poetry" Studies in the History of Culture, 1942 February (Box 42, Folder 942)
    - Original of 'The Complaynt of Scotlande'," Journal of Germanic Philology, 1897 (Box 42, Folder 943)
    - "Overcrowding in Women's Colleges," The Nation: ms., 1925 May 13 (Box 42, Folder 944)
    - "The Question of the Women's Colleges" with the presidents of the seven women's colleges, undated (Box 42, Folder 945)
    - "Phi Beta Kappa's Women President," The Key Reporter, 1940 Autumn (Box 42, Folder 946)
    - "Political Silhouettes", undated (Box 42, Folder 947)
    - "The Preaching Scot," Harvard Monthly, 1902? May (Box 42, Folder 948)
    - "The Process of Reading" Journal of Adult Education, 1938 June (Box 42, Folder 949)
    - "The Process of Peace": ms., 1930 January 24 (Box 42, Folder 950)
    - "The Purgatory of Cruel Beauties": reprint, undated (Box 42, Folder 951)
    - Report of the President, Smith College, 1925-1926 (Box 42, Folder 952)
    - "The Responsibility of the Parent," Reader's Digest, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 953)
    - Roads to Knowledge: introduction, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 954)
    - Roads to Knowledge: miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 955)
    - "Robert Louis Stevenson" The Week, 1894 December 21 (Box 43, Folder 956)
    - "The Scots of America", undated (Box 43, Folder 957)
    - "Laurenus Clark Seelye," Dictionary of American Biography, undated (Box 43, Folder 958)
    - Laurenus Clark Seelye by Harriet Seelye Rhees: Preface by WAN, 1929 (Box 43, Folder 959)
    - "Shakespeare and Plagiarism" Sunday Magazine, 1906 April 22 (Box 43, Folder 960)
    - "Shakespeare in Recent Years" Sewanee Review, 1908 January (Box 43, Folder 961)
    - "Shall We Join the Ladies?" School and Society, 1929 April 13 (Box 43, Folder 962)
    - "Should Women Be Educated Like Men?" Forum, 1929 February (Box 43, Folder 963)
    - Smith College: the First 50 Years by Harry Norman Gardiner: ms. chapters I, III, and IV, undated (Box 43, Folder 964-66)
    - Smith College: the First 75 Years by Harry Norman Gardiner and WAN: text, chapters II-VIII, undated (Box 43, Folder 967-80)
    - Smith College: the First 75 Years by Harry Norman Gardiner and WAN: notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 981-85)
    - Smith College: the First 75 Years by Harry Norman Gardiner and WAN: unfinished typescript, 1946 (Box 44)
    - "Status of Faculties in University Government", undated (Box 45, Folder 986)
    - "The Study of English," Why Study?: ms., undated (Box 45, Folder 987)
    - Syllabus in the Humanities, introduction by WAN (Eliot Foundation of Adult Education), 1932 (Box 45, Folder 988)
    - "Teaching Shakespeare in the Schools", undated (Box 45, Folder 989)
    - "The Theory of Censorship," Atlantic Monthly, 1930 January (Box 45, Folder 990)
    - "Ashley Horace Thorndike," Dictionary of American Biography, 1936 (Box 45, Folder 991)
    - "Town and Gown Today," Journal of Adult Education, 1931 April (Box 45, Folder 992)
    - "The Training School of Psychiatric Social Work at Smith College," Mental Hygiene, 1918 October (Box 45, Folder 993)
    - "Undergraduate Study in Europe," New York Herald Tribune, 1931 August 16 (Box 45, Folder 994)
    - "The Universities and Adult Education", 1930 March (Box 45, Folder 995)
    - "Upper Canada College," The Canadian Magazine, undated (Box 45, Folder 996)
    - "What is the Job of Our Colleges? For Personality Development," New York Times Magazine, 1937 March 7 (Box 45, Folder 997)
    - "What Price Tenure?" Associated Harvard Clubs, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 998)
    - "What the College Has a Right to Expect of the Schools of English," The School Review, 1908 February (Box 45, Folder 999)
    - "Why More Buildings?" Smith Alumnae Quarterly, 1931 November (Box 45, Folder 1000)
    - "William James As Lecturer and Writer," Harvard Illustrated Magazine, 1907 February (Box 45, Folder 1001)
    - "The Women's Colleges Reply," Atlantic Monthly, 1929 February (Box 45, Folder 1002)
    - Years of Building by Caroline A. Yale: introduction by WAN, 1931 (Box 45, Folder 1003)
    - Reviews by WAN A-Z, 1895-1944; undated (Box 45, Folder 1004-08)
  - Correspondence and News Clippings
    - Allegory: correspondence, 1921-1938 (Box 45, Folder 1009)
    - Broadcast Speech--NBC's Handbook for Announcers & Speakers: news clippings, 1937 (Box 45, Folder 1010)
    - Burns, How to Know Him: correspondence, 1917 (Box 45, Folder 1011)
    - The Cambridge Shakespeare: correspondence, 1902-1936 (Box 45, Folder 1012)
    - Chief British Poets of the 14th and 15th Centuries (1916): correspondence (Box 45, Folder 1013)
    - Chief Elizabethan Dramatists Excluding Shakespeare (1911):correspondence (Box 45, Folder 1014)
    - The Collier Classics: correspondence, general, 1916-1919 (Box 45, Folder 1015)
    - The Collier Classics: American Patriots & Statesmen: correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 45, Folder 1016)
    - The Collier Classics: National Defense Library: correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 45, Folder 1017)
    - Collier's Encyclopaedia: correspondence, 1920-1932 (Box 45, Folder 1018-20)
    - Collier's Encyclopaedia: National Year Book: correspondence, 1934-1944 (Box 45, Folder 1021-23)
    - The Complete Plays & Poems of William Shakespeare (1942) with Charles J. Hill: correspondence, 1937-1942 (Box 45, Folder 1024)
    - Charles William Eliot, the Man and His Beliefs: correspondence, 1916-1931 (Box 45, Folder 1025-28)
    - Charles William Eliot, the Man and His Beliefs: news clippings, 1926 (Box 45, Folder 1029)
    - "Charles William Eliot," Encyclopaedia of: the Social Sciences: correspondence, 1931 (Box 46, Folder 1030)
    - English & Scottish Popular Ballads (1909): correspondence, 1905-1907 (Box 46, Folder 1031)
    - Essentials of Poetry (1912): correspondence, 1912-1939 (Box 46, Folder 1032-33)
    - Essentials of Poetry: reviews, 1912 (Box 46, Folder 1034)
    - The Facts about Shakespeare: correspondence, 1922-1932 (Box 46, Folder 1035)
    - The Harvard Classics: correspondence with P.F. Collier's, 1909-1944 (Box 46, Folder 1036-40)